Nike just released their own line of
strength equipment so of course I had to
go and purchase their premium barbell
and during my time with it so far my
favorite things about it or first of all
the aesthetic this is a very beautiful
barbell it's also a multi-purpose bar so
it's going to serve as the only barbell
in your home gym and it's also available
at a pretty competitive price tag which
I'm going to detail in just a second we
got a fun one today let's get right to
[Music]
it
what's up everybody it's Jake back in
the barbin garage gym and for today's
video I'm going to spend some time
talking about one of the hottest drops
in the fitness industry right now that's
right the Nike premium barbell if you
don't know how this whole process works
in this video today I'm going to talk
about a lot but specifically I'm going
to talk about some money some things I
like and don't like about this barbell
and then of course who it's good for now
before I do all of that though I got to
let y'all know that we've reviewed a ton
of barbells on barb. we went ahead and
came up with our own best list so if you
want to check that out all you got to do
is search barbin best barbells it's
going to pull right up for you and you
can find out for yourself which ones we
like the
[Music]
best so let's talk about what I like
about this barbell and I think first of
all we got to talk about the fact that
it is a multi-purpose bar so it's going
to be the only barbell that you need in
your home gym I'm really big on
multi-purpose bars I don't always see
the point in having multiple barbells in
a home gym you know they take up a lot
of space and plus you know it's going to
cost you more money so it's nice being
able to you know spend just a good
amount of money on one single barbell to
serve across all of your lists so that's
really nice now this bar is also
available in three different colors I
think that's pretty cool obviously I
have the orange one gos
go uh it's also available in black and
red so that's kind of cool you know you
can kind of get some customization with
that if you want to it's available in 15
and 20 kg so you know whoever it is
trying to find a barbell you can
definitely go and get it also buy this
barbell at Dick Sporting Goods so I
order this off Nike's website but you
can just head down to Dick Sporting
Goods and go snag it in store which I
think is a very nice thing it's really
you know easily accessible and that's
just a really good thing now the 15 kg
version is going to run you around 290
bucks while this 20 kg it's about 325
I'm going to you know compare these
prices to the rest of the market in a
second but it's honestly a pretty solid
pretty average price tag overall now
this does have a ceramic coating rather
than cak coat like it looks ceramic it's
also very highly resistant to rust and
corrosion so this barbell should you
know last your pretty you know good
amount of time which is a great thing
you also have four needle bearings in
each loading sleeve and that's going to
provide a pretty solid rate of spin as
you go to do some explosive lifts like a
power clean for example but you know
they're not the best overall in my
opinion I've had plenty of other barbell
BS I've reviewed you know dozens and
dozens I've got a bunch right here right
beside me and I got to say there's a lot
of other barbells that provide you know
a faster rate of spin which definitely
comes in handy as you go to you know
rapidly turn that bar in your hands now
the knurling you know it's it's moderate
which is a good thing for you know a
multi-purpose bar but you know as I kind
of get crosseyed and look you know way
up close right here this volcano style
knurling it's I don't it's kind of weird
in my opinion so if any for anybody who
doesn't know volcano style knurling
every single one of these little you
know markings right here dips in like a
volcano so they basically cut the tops
off of every single point
and I've seen so many other barbells
that have you know a deeper crater I
guess you could call it for each every
single marking so it almost looks like
it's more of a hill style nurl and it
just doesn't really give me the best
grip overall now it you know knurling is
you know subjective to every single
individual person we all have different
preferences but for me it kind of leaves
some to be desired a little bit and
that's just you know you definitely
don't want to be compromised with grip I
know I'm going on and on and on about
this but it's definitely worth you know
mentioning to you guys and then lastly
just remember you know this is a
multi-purpose bar so yes you can do any
style of lift you want to do with it but
it's not going to be the best that
anyone lifts so if you're a dedicated
powerlifter Olympic weightlifter or
crossfitter you're probably going to be
better off going after a specialty bar
that you know tailors your style of
lift
[Music]
so once again the 15 kg version of this
barbell it's going to cost you right
around 290 bucks while the 20 kg version
of this bar is about 325 these prices
are pretty you know average for the most
part but there's other barbells that are
you know 125 bucks cheaper or so that
perform I think a little bit better you
know one that comes to mind is a living
fit barbell that bar 20 kg version it's
about 200 bucks that's an amazing price
point especially for how it performs and
like I said I think it performs a little
bit better than this one does right here
another bar that I really like is the
rep Colorado bar it's also 320 I think
the the serak co version is 330 and that
bar also performs a little bit better
than this one right here now I'm not
dogging on this bar it's still pretty
good it's still a pretty solid barbell
especially for Nike's you know first run
at it first go at producing barbells
over time you know especially if they
keep going at it these bars are going to
be really really nice I mean the amount
of resources resources that they have
and the budget that they have and
everything I can't wait to see you know
where where they take you know their
strength equipment
but honestly this particular you know
version of this bar right now I think
you're kind of paying for the Nike
branding for the name cuz I mean 325 you
know there's a $200 barbell right here
behind me that performs better I think
this bar should probably be a little bit
cheaper than what it is but that's just
my honest
[Music]
opinion okay so the same as you know the
rest of this barbell right here these
loading sleeves also have a ceramic
coating and as you kind of you know I
don't know if you can tell but as you
you know put on plates take them off
over time you're going to get some you
know marks right here it's not damaging
the actual loading sleeve definitely
don't get scared about that you I
haven't done it yet um I'm just kind of
lazy about it but you can get a rag and
just wipe that off and most of that's
going to go away this is kind of the
norm right now with barbells and they're
kind of all leaving these little
markings right now with this specific
you know coating on their sleeves so
once again just nothing to be concerned
about now you do have some snap ring
pliers right here and you can take this
you know loading sleeve apart I did it
earlier I don't want to do it right now
it's kind of messy there's a lot of
grease in here and it's just like I said
it's pretty messy but you do have you
know four needle bearings within the
loading sleeve so there's two right here
and there's two right here here and
that's what's creating the spin you know
you can tell right I'm going to compare
this in just a second to another bar I'm
going to pull it out but you can kind of
see right now the spin's not the best it
definitely still gets the job done but
you know you'll probably have more
torque on your wrists and elbows that
you'll have to deal with but I I'll dig
into that more in just a second now you
do have a Groove pattern right here on
the loading sleeves it's kind of faint
but it's definitely still there the
purpose of that is to help keep your
loading plates in the original placement
and they're going to slide no matter
what if you're dropping a barbell over
time so definitely get some barbell
collars just you know for your own
safety also before I move on I also
really like how this is tapered down
right here makes it a little bit easier
for you to you know slide your plates on
and off which I just like so let's move
in the rack so remember this is a a
medium moderate knurling and it's listed
as a volcano style nurl but once again
you know all these markings they don't
dip in as deep as some other ones that
I've seen and I think that's kind of
hindering my grip at certain times also
you know this is a coated bar so if you
have a stainless steel bar even a bare
steel bar you're going to be able to
achieve a better grip than you can with
one like this so definitely just kind of
keep that in mind now you do have dual
neural markings right here so for those
who don't know this outer marking that's
for the international weightlifting
Federation iwf on the inside's ipf
international powerlifting Federation so
it's just nice how you know that's
official I guess you could say and you
know just kind of get that identical
hand place and all of that stuff now you
don't have a center neurl right here
this is the norm with multi-purpose bars
I you know enjoy not having that
powerlifting bars are going to have that
and a lot of people like that because it
helps you know the bar stick to your
upper back as you're going to do some
back squats so you know you can go both
ways about it if you want to now this
bar is 86 in long and the loading
sleeves are 16.3 in long so pretty
average overall it's pretty much also
the norm with multi-purpose bars now
obviously have the orange one right here
this the ceramic coating at the orange
one it's also available in black and red
so you can kind of you know get your own
little aesthetic going with that this
barbell also has a tensil strength
rating of 190,000 PSI so for those who
don't know tensil strength basically is
just going to tell you you know how
strong a barbell is and pretty much how
much force and everything it can endure
before it starts to lose its you know
original shape it's intended shape
190,000 it's pretty solid it's pretty
much what you're getting with you know a
weightlifting bar because that's going
to have a decent amount of whip actually
a pretty high amount of whip and whip is
the amount of bounce that occurs mid
lift during a power clean for example so
190k that's pretty solid it's also
strong enough to handle plenty of
powerlifting I don't think you're going
have to worry about this barbell
breaking or anything like that at all if
you do break it let me know that'd be
actually kind of cool to see uh but so
just give me one second I want to grab
another barbell and just set it up right
here beside it so you can kind of just
see the difference in the spin rate all
right so let's just compare this the
spin rate real really quick so this is
the living fit barbell and both of these
bars have you know four needle bearings
in the loading sleeve so you're you have
the same Hardware in both all right so
let's start with the Nike one just for a
second spins all right here we
go let's do this again Watch I'll do
this one first and
look it they stopped at the same time
but I started this one ear earlier
obviously so you definitely have a you
know a more rapid spin rate with this
living fit bar remember it's about
$125
cheaper so you know if you're somebody
who's wanting to incorporate you know
Olympic style weightlifting and Crossfit
and you know that kind of style of lift
you're going to be better off you know
with this one specifically just because
of that extra spin rate and you're going
to have less you know torque that you
have to endure on your wrists and your
elbows so basically it's going to be
more successful and everything like that
now this definitely still gets the job
done just maybe not at the same level as
this living fit bar does so when we talk
about you know who should or maybe
shouldn't purchase this barbell I think
you know this is great for anybody who
wants a barbell that's really easily
accessible and what I mean by that is
you know going to a local sporting goods
store remember this is available at Dick
Sporting Goods so you can walk in there
you know grab it feel it sort of test it
out obviously they're not going to allow
you to hit some power cleans in the
store that'd be pretty cool but you know
you can kind of get a good sense of what
you're getting from the barbell as
opposed to just you know going to
somebody's website ordering it and not
really knowing what you're getting until
you get it so I think that's a really
great thing going for it it's also you
know once again a multi-purpose bar so
it's super versatile anybody who's
looking to make the most out of their
you know available budget and their
purchase 325 for a bar that can handle
it all is a pretty solid deal and then
Aesthetics alone this is a beautiful
barbell as I mentioned earlier this
looks great you got the Nike branding
right here on the front on the incaps as
well so honestly if you're just looking
for the best looking gear possible this
is one of the sweetest bar builds that
I've seen now on the other hand you know
it's not going to be the best at anyone
lift I me know it's multi-purpose bar
yeah you can do it all but for specialty
lifting you know Olympic weight lifting
power lifting anything like that it's
not going to be you know the best option
overall and then also you can absolutely
find yourself a cheaper barbell you know
that performs just as well if not better
than this one right here so definitely
keep that in
[Music]
mind well that's all she wrote for
today's review over the Nike coded
premium barbell I think this is a pretty
good bar for Nike's first go at it and
it's tested pretty well just remember
you're kind of paying for the Nike
branding and you can definitely find a
cheaper one that performs just as well
as this one does thanks for watching
y'all I hope this video was helpful and
I was able to tell you everything there
is to know about this barbell as always
stay posted for my next video but for
now head over to Barb ben.com so we have
a full written article about this
barbell that you might find to be pretty
helpful all you got to do is search
barbend Nike premium barbell review and
that's going to pull right up for you
you can go over every single thing we
talked about here today I'm going to go
get a lift in I'll catch youall next
[Music]
time